Hey Java Developers,
Need to parse an input source?
Consider using the tokenize API
part of the Scanner class
The Scanner class can handle many input sources
String, File, InputStream, and more
To tokenize an input source
A regex can be provided to Scanner as
a String, or as a Pattern, to define the delimiter
Processing the tokens can be done as a stream with, .tokens()
Or done as loop with hasNext and next
Scanner also provides hasNext() and next() methods
For the types int, long boolean, double, and others
Allowing for checking and conversion to those types
Scanner can take a locale,
allowing for easy localization of data
Like here treating the final value in the line
as a String when used with the US Locale
But as a numeric,
when used with the German Locale
Happy Coding!