Hey Java Developers
Enjoying Stream Since Java 8?
But finding some holes in its functionality
Streams and its supporting types
have seen several updates in recent releases,
Filling in some of those holes.
Let's take a look at a few key changes
Teeing added to Collectors in Java 12
Allows the results of two downstream collectors to be merged
Predicate was updated in Java 11 with the static not
In this example retrieving the minim
and maximum values
from the stream
Predicate was updated in Java 11 with the static not
Allowing for easier definition
of a negation predicate
ofNullable added in Java 9,
provides null safety,
when processing a single item stream,
returning the value if non-null,
or an empty stream if the passed in value is null
iterate was also updated with java 9,
allowing for a predicate to be provided
which functions as a "hasNext"
and is checked before
executing the "next" UnaryOperator
Happy Coding!