Hey Java Developers
Excited for Records
[techno music]
but wondering where they fit in
if you are using JPA for data access
Considering using records as projections
Added in Java 16
Records are transparent carriers of data
And can be defined in a single line
Because of the constraints on Records
They are unsuitable as JPA entities
But can be used as projections
If using straight JPA
Records can be used with
CriteriaBuilders
TypedQuery(ies)
And NativeQuery(ies)
Spring Data also supports Records
If the fields of the Records match the field names of the tracked entity
If the fields of the Records match
the field names of the tracked entity
Spring Data can automatically handle the mapping
Alternatively a JPA query can be defined
Or a custom repo can be used to
handle the mapping of the query results to the record
Happy Coding!