Hey java developers,
Ever needed to define a collection, but getting cramps from all the typing?
Same
Good news, there the Convenience Factory Methods for Collections added in Java 9
With the List factory method "of"
you can quickly define a List instance, like in this example of Strings
The same syntax is also available for Sets, with Set.of
When needing to define a map instance "of" can also be used
but the provided values must match key and value types
of the map in an alternating pattern, like in this example
Alternatively Map.ofEntries can be used with the
java.util.Map.entry static method
for better readability
at the cost of a little extra typing
Happy coding!