Hey Java Developers
JavaDoc has se...
[snoring]
Please don't fall asleep yet!
JavaDoc has seen a number of updates in recent releases,
improving its usability
Key among these changes was the addition of search
part of JDK 9
Search can be a great way of exploring
and discovering the API on official JavaDocs
Search is also available by default in all generated JavaDoc
Several tags have been added improving API definition:
Including Index, which can be used for defining domain terms and acronyms
Hidden, for API documentation you don't want published
SystemProperties, for system provided values
And tags for defining modules features and behavior
Also with JDK 9
JavaDoc is generated in HTML 5 by default
improving its accessibility
Happy Coding!